Guide to the Albert Thomas Papers, 1937-1965 MS 262
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Albert Thomas papers
1937-1965
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Thomas, Albert
MS 262
8 Linear Feet (21 Boxes)
This collection of speeches, correspondences, reports, and photographs documents the work of Albert Thomas, U.S. Representative for Harris County, Texas, from 1936-1966. Albert Thomas was the first Rice Alumnus to serve in Congress. He graduated from Rice Institute in 1920.
Biographical Note
Albert Thomas was the first Rice Alumnus to serve in Congress. Thomas was born in Nacogdoches, Texas, on April 12, 1898. As a child, he attended Public Schools in Nacogdoches and worked in his father's store. During World War I, Thomas served as a second lieutenant in the army. He graduated from Rice Institute in 1920 and from University of Texas law school in 1926. Thomas was married to Lera Millard in 1922. He was elected county attorney in Nacogdoches in 1927, and served there until 1930, when he moved to Houston to become assistant United States district attorney for the southern district of Texas. Thomas was elected to represent the Eighth District of Texas (Harris County) in the U.S. House of Representatives in 1936, a position he held until his death. Thomas served on numerous committees and was instrumental in locating the NASA Manned Spacecraft Center in Houston. He became chairman of the House Subcommittee on Independent Office Appropriations in 1949, chairman of the Texas House delegation in 1950, and chairman of the House Democratic caucus in 1964. Thomas died while in office in 1966 after a long illness.
Scope and Contents
The Collection consists of Thomas' Congressional correspondence. The collection covers 30 years of service by Thomas in the U.S. House of Representatives. Thomas made few speeches on the House floor and attached his name to only a few bills; however, his correspondence illustrates his continuing behind-the-scenes statesmanship. Included in the collection are sections on U.S. problems, legislation (including Albert Thomas bills), Texas problems, Harris County, Houston Port, Pasadena, school districts, universities, campaigns and elections, and speeches. The collection is composed of 21 document boxes containing typescript, typed copy, photocopy, documents, and photographs. The collection comprises a total of 8 linear feet.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Acquisition Information
The Albert Thomas Papers were received on September 2, 1966 from Mrs. Lera Thomas, widow of the late Albert Thomas.
Arrangement
The collection is divided into fourteen series, which are listed below.
Missing Title
Series I: U.S. Problems
Series II: Legislation
Series III: Committees
Series IV: Texas Problems
Series V: Harris County
Series VI: Houston Port
Series VII: Houston City
Series VIII: Pasadena & Other Cities
Series IX: School Districts
Series X: Universities
Series XI: Campaigns & Elections
Series XII: Speeches
Series XIII: People
Series XIV: Personal
General Note
Portions of this collection are availabe online at: https://scholarship.rice.edu/handle/1911/21715
General Note
Portions of this collection are available online at: https://scholarship.rice.edu/handle/1911/77405
Index Terms
Subjects
Public schools; School districts; Universities and colleges; Universities and colleges -- Alumni and alumnae; Politics and government; Legislation; Elections -- Texas; Harbors; Law and legislation
Document Types
corrrespondence; speeches; photographs
Places
Harris County (Tex.); Houston (Tex.) -- History.; Texas -- Pasadena
Subjects (Corporations)
United States. Congress. House; Port of Houston Authority
- Series I: U.S. Problems, 11912 (Box 1-3)
  - Cancer Research Bulletin, 1960; 11948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Civil Aeronautics Authority, 1939-40; 11947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Commerce Department - Bureau of Census, 1940; 11946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Defense Housing, 1940-42; 11945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Defense Housing, 1941-43; 11944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Defense Housing, 1942-44; 11943 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Defense Projects, 1941-42; 11942 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Demobilization, 1946; 11941 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Federal Housing Administration, 1937-39; 11940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Federal Housing Administration, 1939; 11939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Goose Creek W.P.A., 1937-38; 11938 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - H.E.W. Office of The Secretary, Washington D.C. Congressional Liaison, 1961-64; 11937 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - National Housing Agency, 1942-43; 11936 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Navy Department, 1937-40; 11935 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - P.W.A., 1938-40; 11934 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - P.W.A. Proposal Projects, 1938-39; 11933 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Reciprocal Trade Agreement, 1937-39; 11932 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Report on Russia by Vice Admiral Hyman G. Rickover, USN., 1959; 11931 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Southern Interstate Nuclear Compact, 1961-65; 11930 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - U.S. District Court - Southern District of Texas, 1963-64; 11929 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - U.S. Territorial Expansion - Memorial Commission, 1949; 11928 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Veterans Administration Facilities (Contact Unit), 1937-38; 11927 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Veterans Administration Facilities (Regional Hospital), 1938; 11926 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - War Department, 1937-39; 11925 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - War Department, 1939-40; 11924 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - War Department, 1941-42; 11923 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - War Department, 1942; 11922 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - War Department, 1942-43; 11921 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - War Department, 1943; 11920 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - War Production Board, 1941-43; 11919 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - W.P.A. - Harris County, 1938-39; 11918 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - W.P.A. - Harris County, 1940; 11917 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - W.P.A. - Harris County, 1940-41; 11916 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - W.P.A. - Houston Office, 1938-89; 11915 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - W.P.A. - Low Income Housing, 1939; 11914 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - W.P.A. - Washington, 1939; 11913 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Series II: Legislation, 11867 (Box 4-7)
  - Subseries A: Albert Thomas Bills, 11881 (Box 4-5)
    - Bills 78th Congress, 1943-44; 11911 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Bills 79th Congress, 1945-46; 11910 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Bills 80th Congress, 1947-48; 11909 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Bills 81st Congress, 1949-50; 11908 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Bills 82nd Congress, 1951-52; 11907 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - H.R. 5935 - Reginald Wynne Davis, 1951-52; 11906 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - H.R. 6423 - Russell William Karback, 1952-53; 11905 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - H.R. 7387 - Re: Child Care, 1952; 11904 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - H.R. 7570 - Kimie Ishimura, 1952-53; 11903 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Bills 83rd Congress, 1953-54; 11902 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - H.R. 1703 - Janie Ng Chen, 1952-53; 11901 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - H.R. 2437 - Jean May Hopkins, 1953; 11900 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - H.R. 2675 - Mr. & Mrs. Alkos G Giagtzis, 1953-54; 11899 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - H.R. 3465 - John Base, 1953-54; 11898 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - H.R. 3681 - Nathan L. Laufman, 1953; 11897 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - H.R. 3834 - Jerry F. Markantonis, 1953-54; 11896 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - H.R. 4021 - Reginald Wynne Davis, 1953; 11895 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - H.R. 4022 - Lorenzo D. Meadows, 1953; 11894 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - H.R. 4387 - Dr. Roger Post Adams, 1953; 11893 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - H.R. 5467 - Francis A. Reilly, 1953; 11892 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous Bills, 1952-54; 11891 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Bills 84th Congress, 1955-56; 11890 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Bills 85th Congress, 1957-58; 11889 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - H.R. 5678, 1958; 11888 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Bills 86th Congress, 1959-60; 11887 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - H.R. 6679, 1959-60; 11886 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - H.R. 10399, 1960; 11885 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Bills 87th Congress, 1961-62; 11884 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Bills 88th Congress, 1963-64; 11883 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Bills 89th Congress, 1965-66; 11882 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Subseries B: Other Bills, 11874 (Box 6, Folder 1-6)
    - Miscellaneous Bills, 1957-59; 11880 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - National Labor Relations Act, 1940; 11879 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Truth in Fabric Bill, 1939-40; 11878 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Housing Act, 1937-40; 11877 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Wage & Hour Law, 1937-40; 11876 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Wage & Hour Law, 1939-40; 11875 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Subseries C: Congressional & Presidential, 11868 (Box 6-7)
    - Annual Report to the President, 1964; 11873 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Congressional District Atlas of U.S., 1960; 11872 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Congressional District Data Book, 1961; 11871 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Docket, 1932-40; 11870 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Presidential Messages, 1937-39; 11869 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Series III: Committees, 11859 (Box 7, Folder 2-8)
  - Committee on Appropriations - Independent Offices, 1960-61; 11866 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Committee on Ways & Means, 1936-39; 11865 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Independent Offices Subcommittee, 1961; 11864 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Independent Offices Committee, 1962; 11863 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Kennedy - Johnson Natural Resource Advisory Committee, 1960-61; 11862 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Labor Subcommittee, 1937; 11861 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Pensions Committee, 1937-39; 11860 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Series IV: Texas Problems, 11846 (Box 7-8)
  - Naval Base, 1939-42; 11858 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Rayburn (Sam) Library Foundation, 1950-62; 11857 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - San Jacinto Parks Commission, 1960-62; 11856 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Texas, State of - Attorney General, 1949-50; 11855 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Texas, State of - Governor of Texas, 1940-6; 11854 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Texas, State of - House of Representatives, 1962-66; 11853 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Texas Air National Guard, 1957-60; 11852 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Trinity River - Correspondence, 1962-65; 11851 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Trinity River - Livingston Reclamation Project, 1961-66; 11850 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Trinity River - Wallisville Reservoir, 1960-63; 11849 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Trinity River - Wallisville Reservoir, 1954-61; 11848 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Trinity River - Wallisville Reservoir, 1965-66; 11847 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Series V: Harris County, TX, 11826 (Box 8-10)
  - Brays Bayou, 1938; 11845 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Clear Creek Channel, 1938; 11844 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Ellington Field, 1940; 11843 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Flood Control - Harris County, 1937-38; 11842 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Flood Control - Harris County, 1937-39; 11841 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Flood Control - Harris County, 1937-39; 11840 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Flood Control Letters, 1938; 11839 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Fort Sam Houston, 1940-42; 11838 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Harris County Flood & Drainage Project, 1937-41; 11837 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Harris County Flood Control Newspaper Clippings, 1939-65; 11836 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Harris County Flood Control District, 1940-62; 11835 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Harris County Sports Stadium - Newspaper Clippings, 1961-63; 11834 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Harris County Sports Stadium - Fallout Shelter Project, 1961; 11833 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Harris County Sports Stadium - Fallout Shelter Project, 1964; 11832 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Industrial Waste Disposal Corporation, 1959; 11831 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Industrial Waste Disposal Corporation, 1959; 11830 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Industrial Waste Disposal Corporation, 1960; 11829 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Juvenile Delinquency & Youth Offenses, 1962; 11828 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Wooster Water & Sanitary Improvement Committee, 1941; 11827 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Series VI: Houston Port, 11809 (Box 11-12)
  - Houston, City of - Port of Houston - Food & Drug Laboratory, 1961-62; 11825 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Houston, Port of, 1937-42; 11824 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Houston, Port of, 1942-47; 11823 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Houston, Port of, 1947-51; 11822 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Houston, Port of, 1951-53; 11821 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Houston, Port of, 1954-63; 11820 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Houston, Port of, 1959-63; 11819 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Houston Port & Traffic Bureau, 1939-48; 11818 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Houston Port & Traffic Bureau, 1949-51; 11817 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Houston Port & Traffic Bureau, 1952-53; 11816 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Houston Port Commission, 1963-66; 11815 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Houston Ship Channel - Army Engineers' Report, 1937-41; 11814 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - US Army Corps of Engineers map of the Buffalo Bayou Watershed, 117489
  - Houston Ship Channel - Barbour's Cut, 1962; 11813 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Houston Ship Channel - Resurvey, 1950-55; 11812 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Houston Ship Channel - Resurvey, 1955-58; 11811 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Houston Ship Channel - San Jacinto River, 1956-60; 11810 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Series VII: Houston City, 11766 (Box 13-16)
  - Three Photographs of Houston Areas, n.d.; 11808 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Airplane Plant, 1940; 11807 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Citizen's National Bank & Trust Co., Baytown, 1939-64; 11806 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Depelchin Faith Home Orphanage, 1937-39; 11805 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Hedgecroft Hospital & Clinic, 1946-58; 11804 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Hermann Hospital, 1949-59; 11803 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Hermann Hospital Estate, 1955-1957; 11802 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Houston, City of, 1939-46; 11801 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Houston, City of - Civil Defense, 1951-65; 11800 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Houston, City of - Department of Aviation, 1961-62; 11799 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Houston, City of - Houston Housing Authority, 1939-58; 11798 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Houston, City of - Houston Intercontinental Airport, 1963-66; 11797 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Houston, City of - Houston International Airport, 1960-66; 11796 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Houston, City of - Recreation Department, 1938-43; 11795 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Houston, City of - Urban Renewal, 1959-66; 11794 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Greater Houston Action for Youth, 1961-62; 11793 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Greater Houston Action for Youth, 1962-63; 11792 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Greater Houston Action for Youth, 1964-66; 11791 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Houston Chamber of Commerce, 1937-39; 11790 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Houston Chamber of Commerce, 1939-40; 11789 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Houston Chamber of Commerce, 1940; 11788 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Houston Chamber of Commerce, 1941-43; 11787 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Houston Chamber of Commerce, 1943-46; 11786 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Houston Chamber of Commerce, 1962-64; 11785 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Houston Chronicle, 1937-46; 11784 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Houston Customs Appraisers Warehouse Building, 1937-41; 11783 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Houston Federal Office Building & Courthouse, 1960-64; 11782 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Houston Federal Office Building - Replies to Invitations, 1962; 11781 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Houston Housing Authority, 1937-38; 11780 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Houston Housing Authority, 1938-39; 11779 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Houston Housing Authority, 1939; 11778 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Houston National Guard Coast Artillery Regiment, 1937; 11777 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Houston Negro Hospital, 1942-59; 11776 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Houston - New Orleans Lighted Airways, 1936-38; 11775 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Houston Press, 1937-46; 11774 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Houston Public Library, 1938; 11773 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Houston Pure Food & Drug Laboratory, 1936-37, 1961; 11772 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Houston - Water Division, 1940-64; 11771 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Houston Youth Center, 1961-63; 11770 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Jefferson Davis High School, 1959-60; 11769 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Jefferson Davis Hospital, 1939-54; 11768 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Park Place Library -- P.W.A., 1938-40; 11767 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Series VIII: Pasadena and Other Cities, 11751 (Box 16-17)
  - Bellaire Sewer Project, 1938-39; 11765 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - City of West University Place Water Works Project, 1939; 11764 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - City of West University Place W.P.A., 1940; 11763 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Goose Creek Street Project, 1939-40; 11762 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Humble Cantonment, 1941; 11761 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Two Maps of Pasadena, n.d.; 11760 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Pasadena, City of, 1956-65; 11759 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Pasadena Armory, 1956-60; 11758 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Pasadena Street Improvement Project, 1939-40; 11757 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Pelly City of, (R.F.C.), 1939; 11756 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Shoreacres, Village of, 1957-63; 11755 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Tomball, City of, 1941-60; 11754 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Tomball Hospital, 1946-49; 11753 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Wilshire Village, 1939-40; 11752 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Series IX: School Districts, 11738 (Box 17, Folder 6-17)
  - Aldine Independent School District, 1938-45; 11750 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Almeda School District, 1937; 11749 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Cedar Bayou Independent School District, 1938-46; 11748 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Channelview Common School District #18, 1938; 11747 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Channelview Independent School District, 1946-54; 11746 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Galena Park Public Schools, 1941-45; 11745 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Goose Creek Independent School District, 1936-39; 11744 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Goose Creek Independent School District, 1951-52; 11743 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Houston Independent School District, 1938-42; 11742 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - North East Houston Independent School District, 1938-66; 11741 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Pasadena Independent School District, 1937-46; 11740 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Spring Branch Independent School District, 1938-56; 11739 (Box 17, Folder 17)
- Series X: Universities, 11733 (Box 17-18)
  - Rice Institute, 1937-46; 11737 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Rice Institute Re: Atomic Energy, 1956-58; 11736 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - University of Houston, 1937-40; 11735 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Stephen F. Austin State College, 1963-66; 11734 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Series XI: Campaigns and Elections, 11706 (Box 18-19)
  - Subseries A: Campaigns, 11725 (Box 18-19)
    - Campaign - Labor Endorsements, 1940; 11732 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Files on Campaigns, 1930-46; 11731 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Files on Campaigns, 1940; 11730 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Files on Campaigns, 1937-61; 11729 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Files on Campaigns, 1940; 11728 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Files on Campaigns, 1961-66; 11727 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Kennedy - Johnson Campaign, 1960; 11726 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Subseries B: Elections, 11707 (Box 19)
    - Committee on Elections #3, 1940; 11724 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Committee on Elections #3, 1940; 11723 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Election Results, 1936; 11722 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Election Results, 1938; 11721 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Election Results, 1940; 11720 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Election Results, 1942; 11719 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Election Results, 1944; 11718 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Election Results, 1946; 11717 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Election Results, 1948; 11716 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Election Results, 1950; 11715 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Election Results, 1952; 11714 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Election Results, 1954; 11713 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Election Results, 1956; 11712 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Election Results, 1958; 11711 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Election Results, 1960; 11710 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Election Results, 1962; 11709 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Election Results, 1964; 11708 (Box 19, Folder 20)
- Series XII: Speeches, 11698 (Box 20)
  - Thomas Speeches, 1938-41; 11705 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Thomas Speeches, 1940-63; 11704 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Thomas Speeches, 1942-43; 11703 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Thomas Speeches, 1943-46; 11702 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Thomas Speeches - Congressional Record, 1942-44; 11701 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Thomas Speeches - Congressional Record, 1947; 11700 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Thomas Speeches - Radio, 1942-43, 1948; 11699 (Box 20, Folder 7)
- Series XIII: People, 11684 (Box 21, Folder 1-13)
  - Baruch, Bernard, 1949-50; 11697 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Biggers, E.M., 1935-40; 11696 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Cannon, Clarence, 1942-62; 11695 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Gonzales Menchaca, - Edilberto, 1952-53; 11694 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Hubert Humphrey Letters & Autographed Speech, 1965-66; 11693 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Jaworski, Leon, 1949-63; 11692 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1957-66; 11691 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Lintelman, Fred H., 1943-47; 11690 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Rayburn, Sam (Hon.), 1936-65; 11689 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Sheppard, Morris (Hon.), 1937-41; 11688 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Steelman, John R., 1947-50; 11687 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Truman, Harry S., 1956-64; 11686 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Visitors to Washington, 1954-58; 11685 (Box 21, Folder 13)
- Series XIV: Personal, 11677 (Box 21, Folder 14-19)
  - About Albert Thomas (includes some photos), 1963; 11683 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Congressional Record - Eulogies to Albert Thomas, 1966; 11682 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Form Letters, 1942-45; 11681 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence with Constituents, 11680 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Albert Thomas Scholarships, 1962; 11679 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Six NASA Photos, 1966; 11678 (Box 21, Folder 19)